<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>From photons to science</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/feeds/karenyng.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://karenyyng.github.io/</id><updated>2014-12-11T23:09:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>PyTables!</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/pytables.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-11T23:09:00-08:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-12-11:pytables.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pytables.github.io/usersguide/tutorials.html"&gt;Using PyTables to store / organize data is just
awesome!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading this lowers my blood pressure level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pytables.github.io/usersguide/tutorials.html#dealing-with-nested-structures-in-tables"&gt;http://pytables.github.io/usersguide/tutorials.html#dealing-with-nested-structures-in-tables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>AstroData Hack Week conclusion</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/astrodata-hack-week-conclusion.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-24T10:14:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-09-24:astrodata-hack-week-conclusion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;It has been a wonderful week in Seattle.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The organizers have really done a great job in trying
to get the participants together to work on stuff.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And special thanks to Phil who's done a marvelous job to talk to the participants and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;reboot the atmosphere when people are stuck.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The progress of my little project can be viewed at:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hackpad.com/Representing-overdensities-in-astro-data-clustering-KDE-rz6RcKo666V"&gt;https://hackpad.com/Representing-overdensities-in-astro-data-clustering-KDE-rz6RcKo666V&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;And there will be reports of attempts of more smaller &amp;quot;hacks&amp;quot; coming.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>AstroData Hack Week - day 1</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/astrodata-hack-week-day-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-15T22:23:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-09-15:astrodata-hack-week-day-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fernando Perez is giving the lecture about ipython notebook this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some notes of the interesting ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;import all the dependencies when you try to export some cell content into a function
you can use
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;%celltofunc&lt;/tt&gt;
but it is still work in progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jinja template files for conversion to ipynb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ipython nbconvert &lt;span class="pre"&gt;--to&lt;/span&gt; python &lt;span class="pre"&gt;--template=simplypython.tpl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;convert ipynb as documentation in sphinx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jake Vanderplas took over just now to teach efficient programming in
numpy (!!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;he talked about how to use the reduce ufunc ... that I almost never use but is useful to know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to Fernando about cool coding + collaboration stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/"&gt;https://gitter.im/&lt;/a&gt; - for any public git repos you can a start a conversation with any git users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;seaborn is a nice high-level library for plotting data sets, even if they are in pandas data frame format!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;virtual machines with packages shipped with an ipynb that documents the data analysis of a paper, using starclusters ......&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupyter - people are trying to make ipython notebook more inclusive since it can communicate not only with python but with Julia and R! &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jupyter.org/"&gt;http://jupyter.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some statistics from astrophysics perspective&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan Foreman-Mackey gave a presentation on the application of Gaussian
processes of detecting exolents or what's known as Kriging in
geophysics. And he recommended some online books at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gaussianprocess.org/gpml/"&gt;http://www.gaussianprocess.org/gpml/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>SFAA talk on El Gordo</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/sfaa-talk-on-el-gordo.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-21T01:03:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-08-21:sfaa-talk-on-el-gordo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/screen-shot-2014-08-20-at-11-54-06-pm.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Screen Shot 2014-08-20 at 11.54.06 PM" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/screen-shot-2014-08-20-at-11-54-06-pm.png?w=300" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just gave a public talk on El Gordo, the galaxy cluster that I've been
working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is almost exactly one year after I gave a more technical talk on
the same cluster in my PhD candidacy exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the slides are at ......&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://slideslive.com/38891780/el-gordo"&gt;http://slideslive.com/38891780/el-gordo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Bayesian Logical Data Analysis in the Physical Sciences</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/bayesian-logical-data-analysis-in-the-physical-sciences.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-18T21:18:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-06-18:bayesian-logical-data-analysis-in-the-physical-sciences.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bayesian Logical Data Analysis in the Physical Sciences" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/41hnrzmbxml.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my new favorite book about Bayesian stat that I learned about
from the Penn. State Astrostat summer school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that it's written by an astronomer and provides Mathematica code
(can't get more astro/ physics than that!!! i think only physicists /
astrophysicists have such a love for Mathematica which is very expensive
in my opinion ... )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I have been reading about sample comparison:
Given two samples, determine if they come from the same distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For such a problem, frequentists assume a null hypothesis that the
samples are different then do some tests to reject the null hypothesis.
Bayesians evaluate the probability of different cases when....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;means being the same, variances being the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;means being the same, variances being different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;means being different, variances being the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mean being different and variances being different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details, read Appendix C of the book.
Is this what I want for answering the scientific question that I have
in mind?
I am not sure.
I have to think harder / talk to some Bayesians.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Extragalactic astronomy and cosmology 2</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/extragalactic-astronomy-and-cosmology-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-15T23:10:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-06-15:extragalactic-astronomy-and-cosmology-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extragalactic astronomy and cosmology 2" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/telescope_names.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fig Credit: (one of my favorite comics - XKCD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today i'm reading the intro part of the book that talks about different
types of telescopes. I might have read it before but i guess i should be
familiar with them. When I talk with my fellow astronomer friends, I
want to know which telescope they are referring to ... where it is, what
it is for etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I only aim to read about radio telescopes because they came
first in the book.
Radio wavelengths are some of the few wavelengths that we can observe
on earth from lambda ~ 5 mm to ~30 m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important features that people try to detect in the radio wavelengths
include&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the 21-cm emission line which is a sign of neutral hydrogen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.2 mm feature for high redshift galaxy ... maybe they r looking at X-band dropouts? (where X is some photometry bands)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important telescopes include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VLA in New Mexico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arecibo telescope in Puerto Rico which is the largest single dish radio non-steerable telescope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Clerk Maxwell telescope on Mauna Kea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VLBI, very large baseline inferometry (VLBI) which consists of multiple telescopes on several continents so they can have different baselines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And i know there should a few more radio arrays coming online all around
the world doing exciting early universe cosmology &amp;nbsp;(e.g. for the epoch
of reionization). They are going to have massive data sets according to
people I met at Penn. State. Hopefully they will also figure out what to
do with the massive data and get good science out of them :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="telescopes"></category><category term="astronomy"></category></entry><entry><title>Feynman lecture on Physics</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/feynman-lecture-on-physics.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-29T23:57:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-05-29:feynman-lecture-on-physics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Feynman lecture on Physics" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/61rrhhcxhxl-_sy300_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always liked Feynman as a physicist - I felt like his lectures
might be too good not to be read during grad school. Today I am reading
the E&amp;amp;M part - since I am a E&amp;amp;M TA this quarter. I am starting from the
very first chapter where he describes the basics - you can usually tell
if the book 's good if the author can go through the basic math in a
crystal clear way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot believe how he verbalized Gauss' law and the concept of and
divergence
It is just mind blowing - every undergrad should have learned it this
way - i.e. to understand what's going on before looking at the math
symbols! He put:
(Electric)
flux = (average normal component ) * (surface area)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Magnetic)
circulation = (avg. tangential component) * (distance of the loop)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so that Gauss' law can simply be verbalized as
flux of E field through any closed surface = enclosed charge / epsilon_naught&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are just some really very simple and easy to understand words that
hides all the complicated math from first time learners. Sometimes I
really hope that I have the clarity to promote physics concepts like
these to my students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a TA and a physics student myself, I experience all too often that
once a student starts fearing a subject, i.e. once s/he sees the
complicated math, s/he stops thinking about what's going on and just
tries to pull whatever seems relevant for solving a problem. They would
not make the equations / math / the physical model adapt to the problem
but just substitute whatever seems convenient. Setting up the problem
correctly allows you to get through 90% of the problem, the rest is
usually just algebra / computation. Students often do not see that.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it's good that the Feynman lectures are at an undergrad level so
it's still quite light of a reading. Hopefully I will get through all
three volumns then start reading some graduate level books such as
Landau and Liftshitz.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Practical Statistics for Astronomer</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/practical-statistics-for-astronomer.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-28T22:04:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-05-28:practical-statistics-for-astronomer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Practical Statistics for Astronomer" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/815vfrmyp8l-_sl1500_.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To best honest I never read the book very carefully when it was used
as the text for my 2nd year cosmology data analysis class (sorry Chris).
It is actually quite a fun read since it started by describing the
important stat. developments throughout history in the first chapter and
then goes through the basics. There isn't a lot of math so it's easy to
skim through. The best point is that the examples are very relevant and
point out common pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example in astronomy a lot of stuff is in power law form, turns
out a power-law distribution does not fit the formal definition of a
p.d.f., (i.e. p.d.f. has to be &amp;gt; 0, and integrates to 1) and that the
binning of data that follows power law distribution has to be taken with
care etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would give it bonus points for including a lot of Bayesian stuff and
giving good comparisons between the Frequentists and Bayesian views. :D&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="statistics"></category><category term="astronomy"></category></entry><entry><title>Extragalactic Astronomy and Cosmology</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/extragalactic-astronomy-and-cosmology.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-27T23:33:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-05-27:extragalactic-astronomy-and-cosmology.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extragalactic Astronomy and Cosmology" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/51hiovcekll.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely one of my favorite text on extragalactic astronomy, so fond
of it that I actually owned a physical copy of the text. Today I am
reading a subsection on stuff that I work on - X-ray radiation from
clusters of galaxies :D&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="extragalactic astronomy"></category><category term="favorite book"></category><category term="cosmology"></category></entry><entry><title>Python and HDF5</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/python-and-hdf5.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-24T17:11:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-05-24:python-and-hdf5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Python and HDF5" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/512k43xgxml.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a saturday so I get to choose what type of books that I read at
my &amp;quot;leisure time&amp;quot;.
As a continuation of my quest for trying to use python (well) for my
research I have been investigating the possibility of using HDF5 to
store some simulation results ... HDF5 is a flexible and fast file
format that the theoretical astrophysicists prefer nowadays (also have
to mention that the file format was first designed by my beloved college
UIUC!) I like it especially because of :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fast read time - library &amp;nbsp;written in C, with nice Python wrapper library h5py&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flexible - you can choose a chunk of the data to read, not the entire dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allows metadata to be stored - this is important coz I don't want to have to remember what exact parameters I used for creating a dataset 3 months after creating them, I want the data to be self-documented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data structure organized like directory - beyond the scope of discussion here since I haven't got to that part of the book yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all the book was alright but they should really include a list
of reference of the most commonly used commands.
Here they go (for my later reference):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import h5py
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import numpy as np
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f = h5py.File(&amp;quot;filepath&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;w&amp;quot;) # let's just open a file to write
# create two datasets with names &amp;quot;array1&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;array2&amp;quot;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f[&amp;quot;array1&amp;quot;] = np.ones((100, 1000)) # initialize a big 2D array
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f[&amp;quot;array2&amp;quot;] = np.zeros((int(1e5), int(1e6)))
# easy writing of metadata as attributes
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f[&amp;quot;array1&amp;quot;].attrs[&amp;quot;info&amp;quot;] = &amp;quot;big array&amp;quot;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f[&amp;quot;array2&amp;quot;].attrs[&amp;quot;info&amp;quot;] = &amp;quot;bigger array&amp;quot;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f.close()
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this part about reading and examining the data is a bit lacking from
the book, just tell me that ONE command that I need!:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f = h5py.File(&amp;quot;filepath&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;r&amp;quot;) # read only
# this should give you the keys e.g. [&amp;quot;array1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;array2&amp;quot;]
# so you don't have to remember what &amp;quot;datasets&amp;quot; are actually in the file
# this is the one command to rule them all
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f.keys()
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; f[&amp;quot;array1&amp;quot;].attrs.keys() # gives you the keys to call the attributes
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HDF5 has a weird official syntax for reading data back into python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; arr = f[&amp;quot;array1&amp;quot;][...]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the following alternative syntax works for reading from both HDF5 or Numpy array from a
dictionary, so I will stick to this alternative syntax instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; arr = f[&amp;quot;array1&amp;quot;][:]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which extends naturally to slicing an array:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; arr = f[&amp;quot;array1&amp;quot;][:10]  # read first 10 entries
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on to next topic:
If you have a linux / mac, you just want to check the file structure
quickly,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;at the command line you can do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ h5ls -vlr file.h5
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would spit out the descriptions of the dataset and the keys for
calling the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently not trying to do anything fancy with the hdf5 files yet but
I think it 'd be good to use hdf5 in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="hdf5"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>Galactic dynamics</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/galactic-dynamics.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-22T21:51:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-05-22:galactic-dynamics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Galactic dynamics" src="http://karenyng.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/ebd8224b9da0c4eb85a3c010-l.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was reviewing some basics in astronomy. Stuff such as the
color-magnitude diagram for showing the relationship between the color
and the brightness of stars (weird that astronomers call it
color-magnitude coz it is really magnitude vs color diagram). Was also
glad to see discussions of collisionless encounters (e.g. stuff that i
work on)
Great book for reviewing astrophysics overall, very clear and in
depth. Will aim to read the potential theory part that has more to do
with the dynamical DM simulations that I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="astronomy"></category><category term="Astrophysics"></category><category term="cosmology"></category></entry><entry><title>Debugging python code with ipdb</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/debugging-python-code-with-ipdb.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-22T13:30:00-08:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-02-22:debugging-python-code-with-ipdb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tried a couple of ways to debug python code,&amp;nbsp;including using the &lt;cite&gt;%pdb&lt;/cite&gt;
magic within &lt;cite&gt;IPython&lt;/cite&gt; or use %debug in the postmortem mode.&amp;nbsp;Still
couldn't figure out how to restart the code within the &lt;cite&gt;pdb&lt;/cite&gt; invoked by the &lt;cite&gt;pdb&lt;/cite&gt;
magic without
pdb raising a &amp;quot;restart&amp;quot; error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think maybe the best way is to stick with the ipython debugger,
ipdb which has autocomplete and syntax highlighting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ python -m ipdb myscript.py
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and insert breakpoints with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ b mymodule.py:lineNum
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and &amp;nbsp;debug until the next break point or restart by typing the shortcut
for continue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ c
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which behaves more similarly to gdb that I 'm more used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you want to debug a certain function from another module, set a break
point to step inside that function by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ from module.py import function
$ b function
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and list all the arguments for this particular function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ args
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also execute python code by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ !my_python_code_or_command
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping through the code is also the same as &lt;cite&gt;gdb&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ step  # or s
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite commands is actually&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
$ up
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which moves the debugger state to one state up the stack trace.
i.e. previous line executed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all the functionalities of pdb that I make use of so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other useful tips can be found
at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.python.org/2/library/pdb.html"&gt;http://docs.python.org/2/library/pdb.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to say goodbye to debugging with print statements.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="debugging"></category><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>How to switch apps/windows w/o using the mouse on a Mac</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/how-to-avoid-using-the-mouse-trackpad.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-21T22:33:00-08:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2014-02-21:how-to-avoid-using-the-mouse-trackpad.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you know me, then you would know that I am not a big fan of using the
mouse.&amp;nbsp;Back in the old days when I used linux, I could customize most of
the keyboard shortcuts so it was easy to stay with the keyboard without
using the mouse.&amp;nbsp;Lol even though I did set up expośe with my linux box,
it was just for the fun, not out of necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After switching to mac, I got distracted and never actually learned how
to navigate with the keyboard only. It was also one of the grudges that
I first had against using a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today, I have finally found what I want!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cmd Tab - helps you switch between applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cmd &amp;nbsp;` (this is the grave accent sign, not tilde) helps you switch
between different windows of the same application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyData 2013</title><link href="http://karenyyng.github.io/pydata-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-06T15:13:00-07:00</updated><author><name>karenyng</name></author><id>tag:karenyyng.github.io,2013-04-06:pydata-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vimeo.com/pydata/videos/page:1/sort:date"&gt;PyData 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really rewarding experience going to PyData and I am pleasantly
surprised that the organizers have uploaded the talks already
:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vimeo.com/pydata/videos/page:1/sort:date"&gt;https://vimeo.com/pydata/videos/page:1/sort:date&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Particularly good talks include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vimeo.com/63256380"&gt;https://vimeo.com/63256380&lt;/a&gt;- given by the CEO of Continuum Analytics
talking about the next generation Python scientific computing package
called Blaze which is optimized for big data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://vimeo.com/63250251"&gt;https://vimeo.com/63250251&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- keynote talk by Fernando Perez on
ipython.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="PyData"></category></entry></feed>